This lesson focuses on two main concepts.
这节课主要分成两部分
1. Checking if your data fits a normal distribution.
第一部分是检查数据是否为正态分布
2. Checking if your data is
并检查数据是否保持不变
stationary over time and what to do in
如果这两种情况不满足
both cases when they're not.
该怎么办
To understand regression which we will
第二部分会介绍回归
build upon later in time series analysis
之后讲解时序分析时会用到回归
when using regression, we choose one or
在使用回归时
more independent variables to help us
我们会选择一个或多个自变量
predict a dependent variable.
用来预测因变量
Independent variables may include market indices,
自变量包括市场指数
employment numbers, weather forecasts or
雇佣数据 天气预报
consumer spending reports.
或消费者支出报告
Dependent variables include stock price returns,
因变量包括股价收益
but may also include electricity
还可能包括耗电量
consumption or the amount of corn harvested.
或者玉米收成
You can also choose stocks
还可以在回归中
returns as both your independent and
将股票收益同时当做
dependent variables in a regression.
自变量和因变量
At first glance it looks like you're using
咋一看
the returns of one stock to predict the
好像是用一个股票的收益
returns of another stock. In fact the
预测另一个股票的收益
regression is used to see how two assets
实际上 回归是用来查看
or two groups of assets move in relation
两个资产或两组资产
to each other. This is what we do in
相互移动的关系
statistical arbitrage. Statistical
这就是在统计套利中采取的做法
arbitrage is a trading technique that
统计套利是一种交易技巧
involves simultaneously buying and
我们根据两个资产
selling two related assets based on the
相互移动的关系
analysis of how these two assets move in
同时买入和卖出
relation to one another. It's important
两个相关的资产
to keep in mind the signal-to-noise
需要注意数据中的
ratio in our data. The signal is the
信噪比
meaningful part of our input data that
信号是指有助于预测因变量的
helps us predict our dependent variable.
有意义输入数据部分
The noise is the random part of our data
噪点是指数据中
that does not help us make better
不能帮助我们更好地做出预测的随机部分
predictions. With financial data, the
对于金融数据来说
signal is relatively low and there is a
信号相对来说较弱
lot of noise. In other words, the
有很多噪点
signal-to-noise ratio tends to be low.
也就是说 信噪比很低
When the signal-to-noise ratio is low,
当信噪比很低时
predictive models tend to overfit the
预测模型往往会
data that it's trained on. This means
过拟合训练数据
that when the model is used to make
如果在现实中
forecasts in real life, they often pay
使用这些模型进行预测
too much attention to aspects of the
模型通常会过于注重
data that are not actually useful in
对预测来说作用不大的
prediction.
数据部分
This results in predictions that are not
导致预测不够准确
accurate enough to be useful.
因此作用不大
Moreover the relationship between the
此外 自变量和股票收益
independent variables and the stock
之间的关系
returns can change over time. In other
可能会逐渐变化
words, their relationships are not
也就是说 它们的关系不稳定
stationary in practice. This means that
在实践中 这种模型
your models become stale after some time
过一段时间后就过时了
and need to be periodically retrained
需要用更新的数据
with more recent data. This also means
定期重新训练
that some independent variables that
并且某些自变量
produced useful predictive signals in
过去能够生成有用的预测信号
the past may not necessarily do so in
但是未来就不一定了
the future and vice-versa. This is partly
反之亦然
why a certain trading strategies fade
所以某些交易策略
after a while and become useful again in
过段时间后失效了
the future.
在未来又变得有用